Guide to the Sighle Kennedy papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Scholarly material for projected Watt monograph, 1969-1996
  - Subseries III.5: Assigned research material for Watt monograph, undated
    Placed here are the research materials Kennedy had gathered for specific sections of the Watt project. The folders in which these photocopies were contained, and some of the documents themselves, are labeled with section numbers. The assignments themselves are occasionally unclear — some documents have more than one section number written on them — but every effort has been made to reproduce as much of the structure of Kennedy’s projected monograph as is possible based on the organization of her research materials.
    - Introduction (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Sections Ib and Ic (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Section II, "Game" (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Section IIb (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Section IId (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Section III (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Subseries III.6: Unassigned research material for Watt monograph, undated
    This small subseries contains research materials which Kennedy had not assigned to a section of her Watt study. They include newspaper clippings, photocopies taken from books — including the published German-language director’s book for Waiting for Godot — and a photocopy of an untitled document which details, in English, the changes Beckett made to the Godot script when he directed the play in German in 1975. Also placed here are photocopies and photographs of paintings — by Caspar David Friedrich, Giuseppe Maria Crespi, Giovanni Bellini, James Slatney and Hieronymus Bosch — related to Kennedy’s Watt research.
    - Photocopies of articles, news clippings, and encyclopedia entries (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Material on Beckett's Regiebuch for Warten auf Godot (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Photographs and photocopies of paintings related to Watt research (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Series IV: Scholarly material for related projects on Beckett, circa 1978-1996
  Series IV houses notebooks, loose notes, note cards, drafts, and research materials on Beckett’s relationships to other writers and thinkers. While these studies may have emerged from Kennedy’s work on Watt — and in fact some of her Watt notes appear intermittently here — the projects seem to have eventually taken on a life of their own, and contributed to at least one of Kennedy’s published articles and to another projected book (on Beckett and Dante).
  - Subseries IV.1: Beckett and Arnold Geulincx, 1985-1989
    Subseries 1 features notes, drafts, and photocopied research material related to Kennedy’s research on the connections between Beckett’s writing and that of Arnold Geulincx, a seventeenth-century Flemish philosopher whose work concerned ethics and the mind-body relationship. Related articles on Erasmus also appear here. Many of these materials are annotated by Kennedy.
    - Map of the Netherlands, in pencil, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Notes and drafts, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Notes and drafts, 1985-1989 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Research material on Geulincx and Beckett, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Research material on Geulincx and Beckett, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Research material on Geulincx and Erasmus, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Subseries IV.2: Beckett and Dante, 1980-1996
    Subseries 2 contains notes and drafts Kennedy produced during her study of Beckett’s relationship to Dante. The bulk of the grouping consists of Kennedy’s research material: photocopies of literary works, scholarly articles and chapters, and occasionally encyclopedia entries, on Dante and related writers including Augustine, Aquinas, Democritus, and Peter Abelard. Many, but not all, of these photocopies are annotated by Kennedy. Most of the scholarly articles are in English, though some are in Italian.
    - Notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Notes, circa 1980 "Samuel Beckett's Dante 'Revelation'" (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Notebook, 1986-1991 "Beckett, Belacqua and the Sphere of Fortune" (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Notebook, 1988-1990 "Beckett and Dante and Geulincx" (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Notebook, 1988-1993 "Beckett's moral influences; Dante" (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Notebook, 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Notebook, 1989-1992 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Notebook, 1989-1993 "Huguenot Fantasy; Moral Debt to James Joyce; Beckett's Dante 'Revelation'; Dante and Fortuna" (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Notebook, 1990-: "SB and Debt to Geulincx; Artist at Crossroads (Debt to Joyce); SB and Dante; SB: Beginning and End (early life in Ireland)" (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Loose notes and drafts, 1990-: "Beckett's Dantean Struggle for Liberty" (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Course notes, 1990 September-December: "Sources of the Divine Comedy," ProJoan Ferrante (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Notebook, 1990-1992 "Day Notes" (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Notebook, 1990-1996 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Notebook, 1991 "Drafts: Beckett, Belacqua and the Sphere of Fortune" (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Notebooks and notes, 1991 Beckett and Belacqua (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Notebooks, 1991-1992 "Watt; Belacqua in the Sphere of Fortune" (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Notebook, 1991-1993 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Loose notes, drafts and notebook, 1992 "Beckett's Dante 'Revelation,'" "Beckett's Belacqua" (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Notebook, 1992 "Belacqua and the Sphere of Fortune: Supplementary Notes" (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Notebook and notes, 1992, 1996 On Teodolinda Barolini's The Undivine Comedy (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Loose notes, drafts and notebook, 1993 "Beckett's Dante 'Revelation': Belacqua in the Sphere of Fortune"; analysis of Dream of Fair to Middling Women (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Draft, 1993 "Belacqua and the Sphere of Fortune" (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Notebooks, 1993-1995 "Beckett's Dante 'Revelation'" (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Loose notes, drafts, notebooks, 1994 "Beckett-Dante Relationship" (transcript of interview with Ethne Kennedy and outline for proposed monograph) (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Loose notes, drafts, and notebooks, 1995 "Beckett's Belacqua Explores Dante's Sphere of Fortune" (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Loose notes, drafts and notebooks, 1995 "Beckett's Belacqua Explores Dante's Sphere of Fortune"; Dante and "Fortuna" (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Loose notes and drafts, 1996 "Beckett's Global Dante: Belacqua in the Sphere of Fortune" (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Research material on Dante, undated, (4 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 7-10)
    - Research material on Dante, undated, (6 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 1-6)
    - Research material on Dante, undated, (7 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 1-7)
    - Research material on Dante, undated, (6 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 1-6)
    - Research material on Dante, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Subseries IV.3: Beckett and James Joyce, 1978-1989
    Subseries 3 consists of research materials (including periodicals), notes, and drafts which address James Joyce, and also Beckett’s relationship to his mentor. Three variously titled drafts of an article-length work on the Joyce-Beckett connection allow one to follow Kennedy’s writing process.
    - Notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Draft, undated: "Samuel Beckett's Tribute to James Joyce: A Matter of Integrity" (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Notes and research material for course on Joyce, 1978-1984 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Draft, circa 1984 "Samuel Beckett's Creative Metamorphosis: A Moral 'Bequest' from James Joyce" (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Notebook and notes, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Notebook, loose notes and drafts, 1987-1989 "Samuel Beckett's Long Metamorphosis: A Moral Bequest from James Joyce" (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Research materials, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 8-9)
    - Joyce centenary materials, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - James Joyce Quarterly 10.1 (Fall 1972) and 11.2 (Winter 1974) (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Subseries IV.4: Scholarly material on other writing by Beckett (1929-1983), undated
    Contained in Subseries 4 are annotated photocopies of and notes on other writings produced by Beckett between 1929 and 1983, including Waiting for Godot, the long-unpublished Dream of Fair to Middling Women and Eleuthéria, and many of Beckett’s shorter works (including reviews and poems). Of special interest is the 1962 unrevised typescript for Play, which Kennedy’s attached note indicates was given to her in May 1973. (It is unclear who typed this draft of Beckett’s play, though the corrections to the script are not in the author’s hand.)
    - Annotated photocopy of Dream of Fair to Middling Women typescript, with related materials (1932), undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Annotated photocopy of Eleutheria (1947), with related materials, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Annotated photocopy, transcript and photographs of En Attendant Godot manuscript (1948), undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Notes on En Attendant Godot manuscript (1948), undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Annotated photocopy of En Attendant Godot (1952), undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Photocopies of other writing by Beckett (1929-1983), annotations undated: (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - All Strange Away typescript (1976)
      - "Assumption" (1929)
      - Breath (1969)
      - Cap au Pire (1983)
      - "Cascando" (1936)
      - "A Case in a Thousand" (1934)
      - Catastrophe (1983)
      - "Che Siagura" (1929)
      - Company (1979)
      - "Le Concentrisme" (circa 1928)
      - "Dante and the Lobster" (1934)
      - "Denis Devlin" (1938)
      - "Les Deux Besoins" (circa 1938)
      - "Echo's Bones" typescript (circa 1935)
      - Eh Joe typescript (1965)
      - "The Essential and the Incidental" (1934)
      - "Ex Cathezra" (1934)
      - "The Expelled" (1946-47)
      - "First Love" (1946)
      - "For Future Reference" (1930)
      - "Henri Hayden" (1955)
    - Photocopies of other writing by Beckett, 1929-1983 continued: (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - "Humanistic Quietism" (1934)
      - Not I typescript (1972)
      - "Peintres de l'empèchement" typescript and manuscript (1947-48)
      - "La Peinture des Van Velde ou le monde et le pantaloon" typescript (1945)
      - Play typescript, unrevised version (1962)
      - "Poetry is Vertical" (1932)
      - A Piece of Monologue (1979)
      - "Suite" excerpt, undated
      - "Three Dialogues, Samuel Beckett and Georges Duthuit" (1949)
      - What Where typescript (1983)
      - Worstward Ho (1983)
  - Subseries IV.5: Notes and research material on Samuel Beckett, general (1934-1996)
    Subseries 5 collects notes and research material on Beckett that Kennedy had not assigned to a particular scholarly project. Included are Kennedy’s notecards, scholarly and newspaper articles in English and in French, and a newspaper clipping file that contains articles published from 1958-1996. Also housed here is a group of periodicals containing scholarly writing on Beckett, most of which has been annotated by Kennedy.
    - Notes, general, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Scholarly and newspaper articles in English (1934-1991), (2 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 2-3)
    - Scholarly and newspaper articles in French (1961-1985) (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper articles in English, 1958-1996 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Research material (1938-1973) (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Periodicals containing scholarly writing on Samuel Beckett, annotated by Kennedy,1974-1987
      - Contemporary Literature 15.4 (Autumn 1974) (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Irish University Review (Autumn 1974) (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - James Joyce Quarterly 8.4 (Summer 1971) (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Journal of Beckett Studies 2 (Winter 1976) (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Journal of Beckett Studies 3 (Summer 1978) (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Journal of Beckett Studies 4 (Spring 1979) (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Journal of Beckett Studies 5 (Autumn 1979) (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Journal of Beckett Studies 6 (Autumn 1980) (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Journal of Beckett Studies 11/12 (1989) (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - New Theatre Magazine 11.3 (1971) (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - The Review of Contemporary Fiction 7.2 (Summer 1987) (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Notecards, A-G, undated (Box 19)
    - Notecards, H-Z, undated (Box 20)
- Series V: Other scholarly and Beckett-related printed material, 1970-1996
  Series V features printed programs for a number of events, including productions of plays by Beckett and other dramatists and for conferences devoted to Beckett’s work. Also included here are printed materials on Padraic Colum, William Butler Yeats and A.J. (Con) Leventhal; documents gathered or produced by Kennedy for her teaching; and a few printed items (including maps) that she collected during trips to Ireland and France.
  - Programs for productions Beckett plays, 1970-1996 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Program for conferences and exhibitions on Beckett, 1970-1990 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Programs for productions of plays by other dramatists, 1970-1992 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Printed material on W.B. Yeats, 1974-1993 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Printed material on Padraic Colum, 1972-1981 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Printed material by and about A.J. (Con) Leventhal, 1972-1984 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Teaching materials, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Printed material gathered during Kennedy's trips to Ireland and France, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Series VI: Published scholarly writing by Sighle Kennedy, 1970 - 1990
  Series VI contains typed copies and off-prints of Kennedy’s published scholarly work.
  - Subseries VI.1: Conference papers and proposals, 1979-1986
    One conference paper abstract, for a 1979 talk, and one draft, from 1986, are featured in this small subseries.
    - "Samuel Beckett's 'Art of Pure Interrogation,'" 1979 July (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - "Samuel Beckett's Creative Helix: Novel Bonded to Play/Play Bonded to Novel," 1986 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Subseries VI.2: Published articles, book reviews, and monograph,1970-1990
    Contained in this subseries are off-prints of six articles and a photocopy of one book review published by Kennedy. Her book, Murphy’s Bed, and clippings of reviews of her publications are also featured.
    - "Artistic Coherence." Review of Samuel Beckett's Murphy: A Critical Excursion. South Atlantic Bulletin 35.3 (May 1970), 64-67. (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Murphy's Bed: A Study of Real Sources and Sur-real Associations in Samuel Beckett's First Novel. Lewisburg, PA: Bucknell UP and Cranbury, NJ: Associated UP, 1971. (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - "'The Devil and Holy Water': Samuel Beckett's Murphy and Flann O'Brien's At Swim-Two-Birds." Modern Irish Literature: Essays in Honor of William York Tindall. Eds. Raymond J. Porter and James D. Brophy. Iona College Press and Twayne, New York: Iona College Press and Twayne, 1972. 251-260. (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - "Spirals of Need: Irish Prototypes in Samuel Beckett's Fiction." Yeats, Joyce, and Beckett: New Light on Three Modern Irish Writers. Eds. Kathleen McGrory and John Unterecker. Lewisburg, PA: Bucknell UP and London: Associated UP, 1976. 153-166. (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - "'The Simple Games the Time Plays with Space--' An Introduction to Samuel Beckett's Manuscripts of Watt." Centerpoint: A Journal of Interdisciplinary Studies 2.3 (Fall 1977): 55-60. (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - "The Famine and the Feasting of the Ages: Samuel Beckett's Occult Endnotes to Krapp's Last Tape." Centerpoint: A Journal of Interdisciplinary Studies 3.1 (Fall 1978): 55-60. (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - "Samuel Beckett's Language: 'Danger: Explosive Materials.'" Centerpoint: A Journal of Interdisciplinary Studies 4.2 (Fall 1980): 135-137. (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - "Beckett's 'Schoolboy Copy' of Dante: A Handbook for Liberty." Dalhousie French Studies 19 (1990 Fall-Winter): 11-19. (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Reviews of Kennedy's scholarly writing, 1972-1977 (Box 22, Folder 11)
- Series VII: Audio and visual material, circa 1920s-1986
  - Subseries VII.1: Audio cassette tapes, 1966-1986
    This subseries consists of Beckett- and Joyce-related audio cassette tapes that Kennedy apparently used in her teaching. All but two are copies.
    - The Abbey Reads: A Tribute to Beckett. Barry McGovern Reads "Dante and the Lobster" and "From an Abandoned Work." Dir. Kathleen Barrington. Dublin: Paycock Publications, 1986. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Children's Songs in Finnegans Wake. Brookfield, CT: James Joyce Cassettes, undated. (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - "James Joyce" and "MacGowran Speaks Beckett." Copy, undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - MacGowran Speaking Beckett. Dublin: Claddagh Records, 1966. Copy. Folder includes Kennedy's notes. (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Songs in Ulysses. Copy, undated. (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Songs of Women in Finnegans Wake. Brookfield, CT: James Joyce Cassettes, undated. (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Waiting for Godot. Copy, undated. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Subseries VII.2: Records, LP and Gramophone, circa 1920s-1966
    Included here are two LPs, one of James Joyce reading excerpts of his writing, and one of the actor Jack MacGowran reading selections from Beckett’s work. Three records, which feature recordings of Irish songs and performances of early twentieth century revolutionary speeches, are Beltona gramophone discs produced sometime after 1923. “Thomas MacDonagh’s Court-Martial Speech” is damaged (the disc is chipped on its outside edge).
    - James Joyce Reading. New York: Caedmon, undated. LP. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - MacGowran Speaking Beckett. Dublin: Claddagh Records, 1966. LP. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - "Brian Boy Magee," by Ethna Carberry / "The Rebel," by Padraig Pearse. Performed by Paul Farrell. Glasgow: Beltona, undated (after 1923). Gramophone. (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - "Excerpts from Padraig Pearse's Oration at the Grave of O'Donovan Rossa" / "Excerpts from Robert Emmet's Speech on the Dock." Performed by Val Vousden. Glasgow: Beltona, undated (after 1923). Gramophone. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - "Thomas MacDonagh's Court Martial Speech." Performed by Paul Farrell. Music by J.J. O'Beirne. Glasgow: Beltona, undated (after 1923). Gramophone. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Subseries VII.3: Visual Art and Related Material, undated
    Kennedy owned several small hand-colored woodcuts by Jack B. Yeats, including “The Shanachie,” made at the Cuala Press (owned and operated by Yeats’s sister, Elizabeth Corbet Yeats), two untitled illustrations of a seaside horse race, and one untitled image of a village crier. They are included in this series, as are two Japanese wood block prints by Hiroshige (the accompanying receipt, dated December 1958, guarantees that these are “at least 150 years old”), and one hand-colored card by M. Roberts depicting O’Connell Street. Three of the Yeats and both of the Hiroshige prints are oversized and are located in map case 14-O-2.
    - Hiroshige, two wood block prints (oversized), undated, and receipt, 1958 December. (Folder 14-O-2)
    - Noland, Kenneth. "Song." Postcard, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Roberts, M. "O'Connell Street, Dublin." Hand-colored card, undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Yeats, Jack B.
      - "The Shanachie." Dundrum: Cuala Press (oversized), undated (circa 1910s) (Folder 14-O-2)
      - Untitled print, undated (circa 1910s) (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Two untitled prints (oversized), undated (circa 1910s) (Folder 14-O-2)
  - Subseries VII.4: Photographs, 1963-1974
    This small subseries includes a group of black-and-white photographs of a New York City production of Endgame credited to Alix Jeffry, a prominent photographer of the Off-Broadway theater scene from the 1950s to the 1980s. (The folder in which the photos had been housed was dated 1974, which indicates that the prints were made and/or sent then; the photos themselves may be images of the 1958 American premiere at the Cherry Lane Theater, or its 1962 revival.) A photograph of a sketch in Beckett’s Trinity College notebooks served as the cover for Murphy’s Bed; several copies are included here. Two photographs of Beckett’s abandoned 1963 manuscript “J.M. Mime” — written for his favorite actor Jack McGowran — also reside here.
    - Jeffry, Alix. Endgame production photographs, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 4-5)
    - Photographs Beckett's marginalia in notebooks housed at Trinity College Dublin, undated. (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Photograph of Beckett's manuscript for "J.M. Mime," 1963 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Photograph of Beckett's manuscript for "J.J. Mime" (oversize), 1963 (Folder 14-O-2)
- Series VIII: Books Annotated by Sighle Kennedy
  Housed in four record boxes are books annotated by Sighle Kennedy. Most are paperbacks.
  - Subseries VIII.1: Books by Samuel Beckett in French
    This subseries features titles from Molloy to Compagnie; all but one of these books was published by Les Editions de Minuit.
  - Comment c'est. Paris: Les Editions de Minuit, 1961. (Box 26)
  - Compagnie. Paris: Les Editions de Minuit, 1980. (Box 26)
  - La dernière bande. 1959. Paris: Les Editions de Minuit, 1980. (Box 26)
  - En attendant Godot. 1952. Paris: Les Editions de Minuit, 1970. (Box 26)
  - En attendant Godot. 1966. Ed. Colin Duckworth. London: Harrap, 1973. (Box 26)
  - Fin de partie suivi de Actes sans paroles. 1957. Paris: Les Editions de Minuit, 1969. (Box 26)
  - L'innommable. 1953. Paris: Les Editions de Minuit, 1971. (Box 26)
  - Malone Meurt. 1951. Paris: Les Editions de Minuit, 1969. (Box 26)
  - Molloy. 1951. Paris: Les Editions de Minuit, 1970. (Box 26)
  - Murphy. Paris: Les Editions de Minuit, 1965. (Box 26)
  - Oh les beaux jours. 1963. Paris: Les Editions de Minuit, 1970. (Box 26)
  - Premier amour. Paris: Les Editions de Minuit, 1970. (Box 26)
  - Subseries VIII.2: Books by Samuel Beckett in English
    Some of these books, many of which are Evergreen-Grove paperbacks, are very heavily annotated; Kennedy appears to have purchased second copies of several of them in order to take an additional set of marginal notes.
  - Collected Poems in English and French. London: John Calder, 1977. (Box 26)
  - Company. New York: Grove, 1980. (Box 26)
  - Disjecta: Miscellaneous Writings and a Dramatic Fragment. Ed. Ruby Cohn. New York: Evergreen-Grove, 1984. (Box 26)
  - Dream of Fair to Middling Women. Ed. Eoin O'Brien and Edith Fournier. Dublin: Black Cat, 1992. (Box 26)
  - Endgame. New York: Evergreen-Grove, 1958. (Box 26)
  - Ends and Odds: Plays and Sketches. London: Faber and Faber, 1977. (Box 26)
  - From an Abandoned Work. London: Faber and Faber, 1958. (Box 26)
  - Happy Days. New York: Evergreen-Grove, 1961. Two copies. (Box 26)
  - How It Is. New York: Evergreen-Grove, 1964. (Box 26)
  - Ill Seen Ill Said. New York: Evergreen-Grove, 1981. (Box 26)
  - Krapp's Last Tape. New York: Evergreen-Grove, 1960. Two copies. (Box 26)
  - The Lost Ones. New York: Grove, 1972. (Box 26)
  - Malone Dies. New York: Evergreen-Grove, 1956. Two copies. (Box 26)
  - Mercier and Camier. New York: Grove, 1974. (Box 26)
  - Molloy. New York: Grove, 1955. (Box 26)
  - Molloy. New York: Evergreen-Grove, 1955. (Box 26)
  - More Pricks than Kicks. London: Calder and Boyars, 1970. (Box 26)
  - More Pricks than Kicks. New York: Evergreen-Grove, 1972. (Box 26)
  - Murphy. New York: Grove, 1957. (Box 26)
  - Murphy. New York: Evergreen-Grove, 1957. (Box 26)
  - No's Knife: Collected Shorter Prose 1945-1966. London: Calder and Boyars, 1967. (Box 26)
  - Our Exagmination Round His Factification for Incamination of Work in Progress. CT: New Directions. (Box 26)
  - Play. London: Faber and Faber, 1968. (Box 26)
  - Poems in English. New York: Grove, 1963. (Box 26)
  - Proust. New York: Evergreen-Grove, 1978. Two copies. (Box 26)
  - Rockaby and Other Short Pieces. New York: Evergreen-Grove, 1981. (Box 26)
  - Stories and Texts for Nothing. New York: Evergreen-Grove, 1968. (Box 26)
  - That Time. London: Faber and Faber, 1976. (Box 26)